A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Activities, Series A FA338
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Gifts from NAR
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1954-1963 (Box 83, Folder 689)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1954-1963 (Box 83, Folder 690)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1964-1971 (Box 84, Folder 691)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1964-1971 (Box 84, Folder 692)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1964-1971 (Box 84, Folder 693)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1964-1971 (Box 84, Folder 694)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1964-1971 (Box 84, Folder 695)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass, 1964-1971 (Box 84, Folder 696)
  - Gifts from NAR - Steuben Glass Catalogs, 1956, 1969, 1970, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 697)
  - Gifts from NAR - Suggestions for Gifts, 1959, 1961, 1964-1965, 1967-1969 (Box 85, Folder 698)
  - Gifts from NAR - Wedding Presents, 1954-1971 (Box 85, Folder 699)
    From NAR to friends and children of friends.
  - Gifts from NAR - Wedding Presents, 1954-1971 (Box 85, Folder 700)
  - Gifts from NAR - Wedding Presents, 1954-1971 (Box 85, Folder 701)
  - Gifts from NAR - Wedding Presents, 1954-1971 (Box 85, Folder 702)
- Gifts Presented to NAR - Acknowledgments, 1959-1970 (Box 85, Folder 703)
  A few miscellaneous acknowledgements for gifts to and from NAR.
- Government Affairs Foundation, 1953-1969
  - Annual Reports, 1953-1957 (Box 86, Folder 704)
  - Agendas, Board of Directors Meetings, 1954, 1956-1965, 1967-1968 (Box 86, Folder 705)
  - Agendas, Board of Directors Meetings, 1954, 1956-1965, 1967-1968 (Box 86, Folder 706)
  - Minutes, Board of Directors Meetings, 1953-1955, 1957-1961, 1963-1965, 1967-1968 (Box 86, Folder 707)
  - General Correspondence, 1953-1969 (Box 86, Folder 708)
    Correspondence, memos, clippings, press releases re: finances, budgets, programs, activities, metropolitan and state government meetings, change of name, grant from Ford Foundation; lectures and speeches by Frank C. Moore, president of Governmental Affairs Foundation; President Eisenhower's "Williamsburg proposals" re: states taking more governmental responsibilities and costs, 1957.
  - General Correspondence, 1969-1969 (Box 86, Folder 709)
    Correspondence, memos, clippings, press releases re: finances, budgets, programs, activities, metropolitan and state government meetings, change of name, grant from Ford Foundation; lectures and speeches by Frank C. Moore, president of Government Affairs Foundation; President Eisenhower's "Williamsburg proposals" re: states taking more governmental responsibilities and costs, 1957.
  - Move to Albany, 1959-1960 (Box 86, Folder 710)
    Plans for move from 22 W. 55th St., New York City to State Bank Building, Albany.
  - NAR Contributions, 1953-1968 (Box 86, Folder 711)
    Correspondence re: NAR's contributions.
  - Financial Reports, 1954-1958, 1961-1968 (Box 87, Folder 712)
    Accountant's audits and treasurer's reports.
  - Financial Reports, 1954-1958, 1961-1968 (Box 87, Folder 713)
  - Publications, 1965, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 714)
    "State Constitutional Restrictions on Local Borrowing and Property Taxing Powers," 1965; "Local Government in New York State During the Dutch Period," a bibliography, 1968; "Local Government In-Service Training," a bibliography, 1968.
  - Publications, 1965, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 715)
  - Reports, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 716)
  - National Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1953-1959 (Box 87, Folder 717)
    Correspondence, memos, printed material, transcripts, press releases re: function of the conference as established at the Michigan meeting, 1957; expenses; appointment of George H. Deming as director; reports, summaries of activities.
  - National Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1953-1959 (Box 87, Folder 718)
  - National Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1953-1959 (Box 87, Folder 719)
  - National Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1953-1959 (Box 87, Folder 720)
- Governor's Club, 1965-1967, 1970-1971 (Box 88, Folder 721)
  Organized club of NAR supporters. Lists of members, plans for parties at Pocantico Hills.
- Governor's Club, 1965-1967, 1970-1971 (Box 88, Folder 722)
- Governors Conferences - San Juan Conference, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 723)
  Miscellaneous correspondence, clippings and printed items re: NAR's attendance at Governors' Conferences. NAR's speech at the 1960 conference, "Decade of Dangers."
- Governors Conferences - San Juan Conference, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 724)
  NAR invited attendees of the Governors' Conference and other dignitaries to a day at the Dorado Beach Hotel. Correspondence, arrangements, guest lists.
- Governors Conferences - Other, 1960, 1967-1970 (Box 88, Folder 725)
- Hemisphere Films
  A Museum of Modern Art project based on the film experience of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs. NAR hoped to produce educational films for Latin America. The organization's activities were limited to a few grants and studies. It never produced a film.
  - Board of Trustees Meetings Minutes and Agendas, 1944, 1946, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 726)
    Includes some correspondence on various issues including the bonding of John Abbot.
  - General Correspondence, 1949, 1954-1955, 1960-1965 (Box 88, Folder 727)
    Correspondence and memos re: grant to Museum of Modern Art to finish film of Picasso's "Guernica;" other grants; dissolution of Hemisphere Films.
  - General Correspondence - Harrison, Wallace K., 1943-1945 (Box 88, Folder 728)
    Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, 1944-1946. Correspondence re: formation of Hemisphere Films and OCIAA's film projects.
  - General Correspondence - Husted, James W., 1943-1947, 1950, 1960-1961 (Box 89, Folder 729)
    Counsel to Hemisphere Films. Correspondence re: formation, legal affairs, and dissolution of Hemisphere Films.
  - Dissolution and Distribution of Assets - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1944, 1963-1965 (Box 89, Folder 730)
    Correspondence and memos re: incorporation, tax status and dissolution. Remaining assets donated to American International Association for Social and Economic Development.
  - Dissolution and Distribution of Assets - Legal Documents, 1963-1965, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 731)
  - Dissolution and Distribution of Assets - AIA Printed Material, 1962, 1965 (Box 89, Folder 732)
  - Financial and Insurance Records, 1944-1949, 1952, 1962-1965 (Box 89, Folder 733)
    Correspondence, memos and reports re: securities holdings, taxes, and financial accounting. Invoices and canceled checks.
  - Official Seals, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 734)
    Two hand presses.
  - Project Authorizations, 1944 (Box 89, Folder 735)
    Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs correspondence and memos re: proposal authorizations for film projects in various Latin American countries; records of field expenditures.
  - MoMA Material
    - Minutes, Board of Directors Meetings, 1943-1945, 1964 (Box 90, Folder 736)
      Agendas, minutes, notices of meetings.
    - By-laws and Certificates of Incorporation, 1940, 1943-44, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 737)
    - Certificates of Dissolution, 1944-1945 (Box 90, Folder 738)
      Material re: dissolution; assigning stock to Museum of Modern Art.
    - Chase Bank Checks and Deposit Slips, 1944 (Box 90, Folder 739)
      Samples.
    - Incorporation Applications and IRS Forms, 1944-1945 (Box 90, Folder 740)
    - Ledgers, 1943-1945, 1946-1965 (Box 90, Folder 741)
      Two volumes containing minutes of meetings, by-laws, material re: incorporation and dissolution.
    - Ledgers, 1943-1945, 1946-1965 (Box 90, Folder 742)
    - Memoranda, 1967 (Box 91, Folder 743)
      Memo of 3/7/67 transferring Hemisphere Films files to Rockefeller Family Archives.
    - Statements of Purpose, 1944 (Box 91, Folder 744)
      Drafts of statement from Museum of Modern Art outlining its relationship with Hemisphere Films and outlining plans for projects.
    - Stock Certificates, 1944 (Box 91, Folder 745)
    - Stock Ledger, 1944 (Box 91, Folder 746)
    - Tax Receipts and Miscellaneous Papers, 1942-1946 (Box 91, Folder 747)
      Notes, memos, agendas. Copy of agreement between Museum of Modern Art and Museum of Modern Art Film Library Corporation, 1942.
- India Development Corporation, 1954 (Box 91, Folder 748)
  Rockefeller brothers participated, through Rockefeller Center, Inc., in International Bank project for a development bank in India. A slim file.
- India Development Corporation, 1954 (Box 91, Folder 748a)
  Rockefeller brothers participated, through Rockefeller Center, Inc., in International Bank project for a development bank in India.
- International Graphic Arts Society - Correspondence, 1951-1971 (Box 91, Folder 749)
  NAR a founding sponsor of this organization dedicated to creating and distributing contemporary graphic arts.
- International Graphic Arts Society - Loans and Contributions, 1951-1972 (Box 91, Folder 750)
  Correspondence and memos re: NAR's contributions and loans to the Society.
- International Graphic Arts Society - Reports, 1951, 1957 (Box 91, Folder 751)
- Invitations
  To dinners, lectures, benefits, openings, exhibitions, events, etc.
  - General, 1956-1958 (Box 92, Folder 753)
  - General, 1956-1958 (Box 92, Folder 754)
  - General, 1956-1958 (Box 92, Folder 755)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-L), 1955-1956 (Box 92, Folder 756)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-L), 1955-1956 (Box 92, Folder 757)
  - Invitations to Speak (M-W), 1955-1956 (Box 93, Folder 758)
  - Invitations to Speak (M-W), 1955-1956 (Box 93, Folder 759)
  - Invitations to Speak, 1957 (Box 93, Folder 760)
  - Invitations to Speak, 1957 (Box 93, Folder 761)
  - Invitations to Speak, 1957 (Box 93, Folder 762)
  - Invitations to Speak, 1957 (Box 93, Folder 763)
  - Invitations to Speak, 1957 (Box 93, Folder 764)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 765)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 766)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 767)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 768)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 769)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 770)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 771)
  - Invitations to Speak (A-N), 1958 (Box 94, Folder 772)
  - Invitations to Speak (O-Z), 1958 (Box 95, Folder 773)
  - Invitations to Speak (O-Z), 1958 (Box 95, Folder 774)
  - Invitations to Speak (O-Z), 1958 (Box 95, Folder 775)
  - Invitations to Speak (O-Z), 1958 (Box 95, Folder 776)
  - Invitations to Speak - Foreign Policy Association, 1948-1956 (Box 95, Folder 777)
    Invitations to speak declined.
  - Invitations to Speak - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1949-1956 (Box 95, Folder 778)
  - Invitations to Speak - Temporary State Committee for the Constitutional Convention, 1957 (Box 95, Folder 779)
    Invitations to speak about NAR's work as Chairman declined.
  - Invitations to Speak and to Serve, 1965-1970 (Box 95, Folder 780)
    Most offers of memberships declined, some small contributions given in lieu of speaking.
  - Invitations to Serve, 1959-1971 (Box 96, Folder 781)
    Invitations to serve on committees or as chairman; most declined. A few honorary memberships accepted. Previous to 1958 discarded.
  - Invitations to Gov. and Mrs. Rockefeller, 1963-1969 (Box 96, Folder 782)
    Regrets for invitations to luncheons, dinners, galas, exhibitions, etc.
  - Invitations for Honorary Chairmanships and Memberships, 1966-1970 (Box 96, Folder 783)
    Correspondence re: those accepted.
  - Invitations for Memberships, 1947-1966 (Box 96, Folder 784)
    Invitations to join clubs, societies, associations, etc.; most declined.
  - Invitations for Memberships, 1947-1966 (Box 96, Folder 785)
  - Invitations for Memberships, 1947-1966 (Box 96, Folder 786)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1971 (Box 97, Folder 787)
    Most declined. Previous to 1959 discarded.
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1971 (Box 97, Folder 788)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1971 (Box 97, Folder 789)
  - Personal, 1963-1970 (Box 97, Folder 790)
    Invitations from friends, and acquaintances for dinner parties, receptions, etc. Letters of regret, acceptance, gifts sent. List of invitations accepted, Jan.-June, 1966.
  - Radio and Television Programs, Declined, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 791)
  - Washington, DC, Events, 1953-1958 (Box 97, Folder 792)
    Invitations to dinners, receptions, premiers, etc.: acceptances and declinations.
  - Weddings, Declined, 1965-1971 (Box 98, Folder 793)
  - Weddings, Declined, 1965-1971 (Box 98, Folder 794)
- Italian Interests (Sardinia), 1956-1958 (Box 98, Folder 795)
  Correspondence re: NAR's interest in property on Sardinia; negotiations on possible purchase. No purchase made. Correspondence with Serafino Irelli (NAR's counsel in Italy), Clare Booth Luce, and Oscar M. Ruebhausen.
- Jury Duty, 1935-1939, 1946-1950, 1954, 1956 (Box 98, Folder 796)
  Correspondence re: NAR's requests to be excused from jury duty due to government service and non-residency. Served on Federal Grant Jury in New York City, 1939.
- JY Ranch, 1947-1968 (Box 98, Folder 797)
  Rockefeller family retreat near Jackson, Wyoming. Correspondence and memos re: visits; family trip, 1947; visits of friends; staff; property; mosquito spraying; expenses.
- Loans Made by NAR to Institutions, 1950-1964 (Box 98, Folder 798)
  NAR's miscellaneous loans and guarantees of loans to International Basic Economy Corporation, National Urban League, The Seventh Co.
- Mayor's Business Advisory Committee, 1940-1947
  - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1940-1941 (Box 98, Folder 799)
    Purpose of the MBAC was to facilitate the handling of New York City's problems through cooperative efforts of business, labor, and city government.
    Correspondence between Committee Secretary David Meiklejohn and MAR's office re: NAR's regrets at not attending meetings (NAR was Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs in Washington); memos, reports, clippings on Committee business. Table of organization.
  - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1940-1941 (Box 98, Folder 800)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1942-1946 (Box 99, Folder 801)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1942-1946 (Box 99, Folder 802)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 99, Folder 803)
    Re: finances; offers of assistance with publications and other matters; the future of the Committee, its disbanding and replacement.
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 99, Folder 804)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 99, Folder 805)
  - NAR's Contributions, 1940-1944 (Box 99, Folder 806)
  - Mayoral Correspondence, 1946 (Box 99, Folder 807)
    Between NAR and Mayor William F. O'Dwyer's office re: administrative set up of Committee; incorporation of Commerce Dep't; budgeting; project proposals.
  - Inter-office Memoranda, 1946-1947 (Box 99, Folder 808)
    Between NAR and his staff, associates and Committee members re: purpose, programs, and funding of the Committee. Some discussion of the City's inaction in approving funds for Committee projects.
  - Offers of Assistance, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 809)
    Correspondence from people interested in helping with the work of the proposed Committee.
  - Resignation Letters, 1947 (Box 100, Folder 810)
    NAR and the Executive Committee of the MBAC resigned because of lack of action from Mayor O'Dwyer's office. NAR resigned 3/24/47.
  - Operating Records of the Committee
    - Budget Figures, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 811)
    - Financial Statements and Fund-raising Correspondence, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 812)
    - Charter and By-laws, 1945-1946 (Box 100, Folder 813)
      Draft of charter and by-laws; proposed contract between New York City and Committee.
    - Minutes, Executive Committee Meetings, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 814)
      NAR acting chairman. Minutes of other miscellaneous meetings.
    - Proposals and Plans, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 815)
      Tentative plans, proposals, speeches, proposed Lower Manhattan Crosstown Expressway.
    - Reports, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 816)
- Meetings, Special, 1948, 1951 (Box 100, Folder 817)
  Meetings with Rockefeller family office staff. Economic discussion meeting, 1951; John Davison Rockefeller 3rd's talk on Africa, 1948.
- Memberships
  - General, 1946-1971 (Box 100, Folder 818)
    NAR memberships in various associations, honorary memberships, payment of dues, (A-M).
  - General, 1946-1971 (Box 100, Folder 819)
    NAR memberships in various associations, honorary memberships, payment of dues, (N-Y).
  - Lists of NAR's Associations, 1952-1978 (Box 100, Folder 820)
  - Diplomatic and Consular Officers, Retired, 1953-1971 (Box 100, Folder 821)
    NAR an associate member.
  - Pilgrims of the United States, 1958-1971 (Box 100, Folder 822)
    NAR's election to membership, 1958; printed material, list of members.
  - Social Register Association, 1962-1971 (Box 101, Folder 823)
    Forms for NAR's entry; copies of 1962 and 1971 entry.
  - Sons of the American Revolution, 1965-1970 (Box 101, Folder 824)
    NAR made an honorary member, 1965; honorary patron of 1965 Ball. Other appeals declined.
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Memoranda, 1946, 1949, 1951 (Box 101, Folder 825)
  Random collection of letters and responses: fan letter from Nina Conan Doyle, daughter-in-law of Sir Arthur; maps to Pocantico Hills; dinner invitation from Gov. Thomas E. Dewey.
- New York State Project, 1957-1958 (Box 101, Folder 826)
  A slim file on NAR's private study of New York State issues. Correspondence and memos re: hiring research assistant; status report. Agenda for meeting.
- Opinion Research Corporation, Reports, 1940 (Box 101, Folder 827)
  Reports to NAR on results of Gallup Polls on the Presidential election of 1940.
- Permission Requests - 810, 812 Fifth Ave., 1951-1971 (Box 101, Folder 828)
  Requests to view art at NAR's apartments, most declined. Special permission to some groups. List of art at 810, 1951.
- Permission Requests - NAR Home, Seal Harbor, Maine, 1952-1969 (Box 101, Folder 829)
  Permission to photograph house for various books and newspapers.
- Permission Requests - Requests Declined, 1963-1971 (Box 101, Folder 830)
- President's Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board, 1969, 1971 (Box 101, Folder 831)
  Nothing of substance here. Clipping re: NAR's appointment to Board, 3/21/69. NAR contributions to refreshment kitty.
- Projects - Document Processing Company Proposal, 1957 (Box 101, Folder 832)
  Preliminary proposal for ITEK. NAR did not invest.
- Projects - Mining - Australian Bauxite Proposal, 1956-1958 (Box 101, Folder 0832A)
  Investigation for possible investment, decision not to invest.
- Projects - Mining - Bancroft, Howland, 1955-1960 (Box 101, Folder 833)
  Consultant on mining prospects. Retainer fees.
- Projects - Mining - Cole Gold Mines Proposal, 1951 (Box 101, Folder 834)
  Effort by Robert Woods Bliss to interest Rockefellers in Canadian gold mine venture; declined.
- Projects - Mining - Holland, Henry, 1958 (Box 101, Folder 835)
  Possible mining investments; all declined.
- Projects - Mining - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1952-1960 (Box 101, Folder 836)
  NAR and Laurance Spelman Rockefeller held 1% interest in Canadian mining syndicate. Evaluation of proposals by staff. Rockefeller brothers policy on mining investments for 1956 by Oscar M. Ruebhausen. Retaining of Howland Bancroft.
- Public Relations Staff Lists, 1951-1952, 1957, 1971 (Box 101, Folder 837)
  Staff assignments to Rockefeller brothers; Public Relations Dep't. program.
- Quantico III Meeting, 1956 (Box 101, Folder 838)
  Preliminary meeting to Rockefeller Brothers Fund Special Studies Project. Correspondence re: possible meeting; invitations; consultant fees; arrangements; letters of thanks.
- Queen Elizabeth's New York Visit, 1957 (Box 101, Folder 839)
  NAR's invitation to Queen and Prince Phillip to visit Pocantico Hills, regretted. NAR's offer to be of assistance during visit, politely acknowledged. Remarks of Queen and Vice President Nixon at luncheon.
- Real Estate Corporation, 1957 (Box 101, Folder 840)
  Memo of 6/27/57 from NAR to John E. Lockwood, Francis A. Jamison, and LAB authorizing them to organize the above to "acquire a property meeting the requirements which I have discussed with John Lockwood." No indication of what this was for.
- Rhode Island School of Design, 1945, 1950-1954, 1961, 1966 (Box 101, Folder 841)
  Correspondence re: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Print Room, alteration of galleries by NAR and David Rockefeller; dedication of new center; collection of oriental artifacts in memory of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller by Lucy T. Aldrich; later appeals declined. Printed material.
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc.
  - By-laws and Certificate of Incorporation, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 842)
  - Board of Trustees Annual Meetings, 1945-1971 (Box 102, Folder 843)
    Correspondence, minutes, and dockets.
  - Board of Trustees Annual Meetings, 1945-1971 (Box 102, Folder 844)
  - Board of Trustees Annual Meetings, 1945-1971 (Box 102, Folder 845)
  - Executive Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1957-1963 (Box 102, Folder 846)
  - Executive Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1957-1963 (Box 102, Folder 847)
  - Executive Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1965-1970 (Box 103, Folder 848)
  - Executive Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1965-1970 (Box 103, Folder 849)
  - Executive Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1965-1970 (Box 103, Folder 850)
  - Executive Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1965-1970 (Box 103, Folder 851)
  - Finance Committee, 1953, 1968 (Box 103, Folder 852)
    Minutes, memos re: investments.
  - General Correspondence, 1941-1971 (Box 103, Folder 853)
    Re: reports; studies; meetings; activities; projects; Korean project; miscellaneous topics.
  - Miscellaneous Reports and Attachments, 1951-1966 (Box 104, Folder 854)
    1951 annual report; revisions to 1956 annual report; press releases; statement to Ways and Means Committee on the Treasury Department's proposals for additional regulations of foundations.
  - Program Reports - Africa, 1957, 1963 (Box 104, Folder 855)
  - Program Reports - Chile, 1960-1965 (Box 104, Folder 856)
  - Program Reports - West Africa, 1956-1963 (Box 104, Folder 857)
  - Program Reports - "The Study of Development Planning in Women's Colleges", 1964 (Box 104, Folder 858)
  - NAR Contribution Acknowledgements, 1952-1963, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 104, Folder 859)
    Letters of appreciation for NAR contributions. Memo re: "The Social and Economic Responsibilities of Business."
  - RBF Contributions, 1952-1963, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 104, Folder 860)
    Correspondence and memos re: finances and expenditures; meetings; studies; appeals; contributions; appreciation. Press releases.
  - RBF Contribution to IBEC Research Institute, 1952-1955 (Box 104, Folder 861)
  - Theological Fellowship Program, 1954-1956, 1959, 1961-1963, 1968 (Box 104, Folder 862)
    Correspondence re: candidates. Memos, press releases, printed material.
  - Securities, Purchases and Sales, 1952-1960 (Box 104, Folder 863)
    Accounts, lists of holdings.
  - Special Studies Project
    Related Archival Materials note
    For additional documentation on the Special Studies Project, consult the Rockefeller Brothers Fund Archive.
    - Statement of Purpose, 1956 (Box 105, Folder 864)
    - General Correspondence, 1956-1962, 1965 (Box 105, Folder 865)
      Re: personnel; preparation; panel membership; panel meetings; NAR's letters to panel members; requests for copies of reports; distribution of reports; letters of thanks. Clippings.
    - General Correspondence, 1956-1962, 1965 (Box 105, Folder 866)
    - Membership Lists, 1956 (Box 105, Folder 867)
      Members of report panels I-VI.
    - Inter-office Memoranda, 1956-1959 (Box 105, Folder 868)
      Memos to NAR.
    - Memoranda, Overall Panel and Special Panel Meetings, 1956-1958 (Box 105, Folder 869)
    - Minutes, Overall Panel Meeting, 1957 (Box 105, Folder 870)